Margo Dunn fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Margo Dunn fonds
1968 - 1993
F-115
Q103500199
75 cm of textual records 2 artifacts
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Dunn, Margo
Margo Dunn, actor, writer, feminist and owner of Ariel Books, has been an active force in the Vancouver women's movement since 1966. She participated in the Abortion Caravan to Ottawa in 1970, acted in guerrilla theatre, and taught Women's Studies at Vancouver City College Langara.
Born in Montreal, on March 17, 1944, Ms. Dunn completed a BA in English from Marianopolis College (de l'Universite de Montreal) in 1964. In 1966, she moved to Vancouver and attended Simon Fraser University from 1968 to 1970 working towards an MA in English. Ms. Dunn returned to SFU in 1974 and 1975 to finish work on her MA thesis, "The Development of Narrative in the Writing of Isabella Valency Crawford." From 1977 to 1979 she worked as an editor and taught drama at the University of New Brunswick. She also ran in the 1978 New Brunswick provincial election as a candidate for the NDP. Ms. Dunn has also taught women's studies at VCC-Langara in Vancouver from 1980 to 1990. Ms. Dunn is also a writer and editor; she edited the publication Makara in the 1970s and Room of Ones Own, in the early 1980s. In addition to her professional activities, Margo Dunn is an unofficial record-keeper of the Vancouver women's movement. She collected and stored material that she felt was important to record women's activities in the struggle for freedom and equality. In this role, she was sought out by representatives of various women's organizations and individuals to store and preserve their records.
More recently, Ms. Dunn has been a columnist for X'tra West and Angles. She also contributes opinion and editorial pieces for the gay and lesbian television programs, Prism and, later, Outlook. She also writes and performs her own work and has resumed her early profession as an actor.
published
Full
Revised
Title based on provenance of the fonds.
The fonds is comprised of the records of Ariel Books and a number of subject files compiled or collected by Margo Dunn. Records reflect Margo Dunn's business interest as owner of Ariel Books, and her role as collector of the records of the Vancouver women's movement.
Includes correspondence, financial records, log books, promotional material, catalogues, articles, clippings, manuscripts, artifacts, and ephemera.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Artefacts; Graphic materials; Textual records; Business and commerce; Women
The fonds was donated by Margo Dunn to the Simon Fraser University Archives in a series of accessions from 1997 to 1999.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
The records remained in the possession of Margo Dunn until they were donated to the Simon Fraser University Archives.
Please consult the inventory for the Women's Bookstore Collection, F-111 and the Women's Studies Association of British Columbia fonds, F-75.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available.
- Ariel Books records, 1976 - 1993; F-115-1; 53 cm of textual records 2 artifacts
  published
  Ariel Books first opened in 1974 as a private business focusing on books about women's spirituality, but switched to collective ownership and a more general feminist bookstore format circa 1975. In 1981, when the collective decided to sell the business, Margo Dunn and Janice Pentland-Smith purchased the store that was then located at 2766 West 4th Avenue in Vancouver. In 1983, Margo Dunn acquired her partner's shares and became the sole proprietor of Ariel Books. In 1991, Ariel Books moved to a larger space at 1988 West 4th Avenue, where it remained until it closed in 1994.
  Ariel Books was one of two feminist bookstores operating in Vancouver during this period; the other was the Women's Bookstore (in operation from 1973 to 1996). Indeed, Vancouver was the only city in North America that supported two feminist bookstores simultaneously for such a long period of time. Ariel Books specialized in books for women in such areas as feminist theory, politics, lesbian issues, violence against women, assertiveness, psychology, parenting, birth and midwifery, fiction and the like. Ariel Books also hosted readings by popular feminist writers, and acted as an essential resource for Vancouver women.
  Series consists of records that document the operation of Ariel Books from the period when Margo Dunn was owner of the store, although some records date to when the collective ran the store. Records reflect the purchase and organization of the business, daily logbooks, correspondence, events and general operational files. Includes sales contracts, financial records, correspondence, certificate of incorporation, inventories, catalogues, event flyers, promotional material and 2 fabric banners.
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  - Establishment and organizational records, 1981 - 1991; F-115-1-1; 5 cm of textual records; Predominant dates: 1981-1987.
    Sub-series consists of records that reflect the purchase of Ariel Books by Margo Dunn and Janice Pentland-Smith in 1981, Dunn's purchase of Pentland-Smith's shares in 1983, and other organizational and legal records. Includes registration of the business, sales agreement, conditional sales contract, financial statements, correspondence, resolutions, certificate of incorporation, and inventory lists.
    - Ariel Books - purchase, 1981 - 1982; F-115-1-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 115-1)
      Textual records
      Restricted in whole
    - Ariel Books - corporate documents, 1981 - 1983; F-115-1-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 115-1)
    - Ariel Books - JPS shares purchase, 1981 - 1983; F-115-1-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 115-1)
    - Ariel Books - lease / debenture, 1987 - 1991; F-115-1-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 115-1)
    - Ariel Books - general, 1982 - 1987; F-115-1-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 115-1)
  - Log books, 1978 - 1993; F-115-1-2; 22 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of logbooks that reflect the day to day activities of Ariel Books.
    - Ariel Books - log, 1978; F-115-1-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 115-1)
      Open
    - Ariel Books - log, 1978; F-115-1-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 115-1)
    - Ariel Books - log / minutes, 1980; F-115-1-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 115-1)
    - Ariel Books - daily journal, 1983; F-115-1-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 115-1)
      Pending review
    - Ariel Books - log, 1983; F-115-1-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 115-1)
    - Ariel Books - log, 1983 - 1984; F-115-1-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 115-1)
    - Ariel Books - log, 1984; F-115-1-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 115-1)
    - Ariel Books - log, 1984 - 1985; F-115-1-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 115-2)
    - Ariel Books - log, 1986; F-115-1-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 115-2)
    - Ariel Books - log, 1986 - 1987; F-115-1-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 115-2)
    - Ariel Books - log, 1987; F-115-1-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 115-2)
    - Ariel Books - log, 1989; F-115-1-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 115-2)
    - Ariel Books - log, 1991; F-115-1-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 115-2)
    - Ariel Books - log, 1990; F-115-1-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 115-2)
    - Ariel Books - log, 1990 - 1991; F-115-1-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 115-2)
    - Ariel Books - log, 1991; F-115-1-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 115-3)
    - Ariel Books - log, 1993; F-115-1-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 115-3)
      Restricted in part
  - Correspondence, 1980 - 1993; F-115-1-3; 5 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of correspondence created and received by Ariel Books. Includes records that reflect daily business, special events, purchase and sale of stock, and donations made to various feminist organizations and causes.
    - Ariel Books - correspondence, 1980 - 1988; F-115-1-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 115-3)
    - Ariel Books - correspondence -- May Sarton, 1982; F-115-1-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 115-3)
    - Ariel Books - correspondence -- thank you's, 1982 - 1989; F-115-1-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 115-3)
    - Ariel Books - correspondence 1/2, 1983 - 1993; F-115-1-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 115-3)
    - Ariel Books - correspondence 2/2, 1983 - 1993; F-115-1-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 115-3)
  - Events records, 1986 - 1990; F-115-1-4; 5 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records that reflect events at Ariel Books, and outside events attended by representatives of the store. Includes calendars, brochures, correspondence, and advertising.
    - Ariel Books - events, 1986; F-115-1-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 115-3)
    - Ariel Books - events, 1987; F-115-1-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 115-3)
    - Ariel Books - events, 1988; F-115-1-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 115-3)
    - Ariel Books - events, 1989; F-115-1-4-0-4 (Archival box - standard 115-3)
  - General operational files, 1976 - 1989; F-115-1-5; 16 cm of textual records 2 artifacts
    Sub-series consists of records that reflect the operational activities of Ariel Books, such as applications for Canada Council Assistance for author readings, and donations to feminist organizations and causes. Includes correspondence, catalogues, promotional material, calendars, and artifacts.
    - Ariel Books - inventory, 1982 - 1987; F-115-1-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
    - Ariel Books - catalogue, 1982; F-115-1-5-0-2 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
    - Ariel Books - donations by Ariel Books, 1981 - 1987; F-115-1-5-0-3 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
    - Ariel Books - Canada Council assistance, 1983 - 1986; F-115-1-5-0-4 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
    - Ariel Books - purchase of PERC stock, 1982; F-115-1-5-0-5 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
    - Ariel Books - feminist bookstores, 1982 - 1985; F-115-1-5-0-6 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
    - Ariel Books - Kingston Prison for women, 1987 - 1989; F-115-1-5-0-7 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
    - [Ariel Books - promotional material] file not available, F-115-1-5-0-8 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
    - Ariel Books - Press Gang calendar, 1976; F-115-1-5-0-9
    - Ariel Books - banners (artifacts), [ca 1980] - [ca 1989]; F-115-1-5-0-10
- Subject files, 1968 - 1982; F-115-2; 34 cm of textual records
  Series consists of files that reflect a number of issues, activities, and areas of interest to the women's movement in North America. Files contain material on such diverse topics as unions, rape statistics, the British Columbia Federation of Women, the women's movement in Toronto and Berkeley, and feminist and homosexual periodicals. Includes correspondence, memoranda, newsletters, articles, reports, minutes, periodicals, publications, and posters.
  - Berkeley Women's Movement 1/2, 1969 - 1972; F-115-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
  - Berkeley Women's Movement 2/2, 1969 - 1972; F-115-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
  - Berkeley Women's Movement - newsletters, 1969 - 1972; F-115-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
  - British Columbia Federation of Women (BCFW), 1975 - 1982; F-115-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
  - Female Liberation Newsletter, 1970 - 1971; F-115-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 115-4)
  - National Association of Sexual Assault Centres, 1978 - 1980; F-115-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 115-5)
  - New Democratic Party press releases, 1977 - 1978; F-115-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 115-5)
  - Periodicals and publications - feminist, 1971 - 1972; F-115-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 115-5)
  - Periodicals and publications - general, 1970 - 1978; F-115-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 115-5)
  - Periodicals and publications - homosexual, 1971 - 1977; F-115-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 115-5)
  - Rape statistics, BC - gathered for Rape Relief, 1977 - 1978; F-115-2-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 115-5)
  - Service, Office and Retail Workers Union of Canada (SORWUC), 1976 - 1978; F-115-2-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 115-6)
  - SORWUC newsletters, 1976 - 1978; F-115-2-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 115-6)
  - Toronto Women's Movement, 1970 - 1977; F-115-2-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 115-6)
  - U.S. and International Women's Movement, 1971 - 1972; F-115-2-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 115-6)
  - Women's Studies, 1968 - 1978; F-115-2-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 115-6)
  - Women's Studies Association, 1976 - 1980; F-115-2-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 115-6)
  - Posters (oversize), vol. 1, 1970 - 1981; F-115-2-0-0-18
  - Posters (oversize), vol. 2, 1970 - 1981; F-115-2-0-0-19
  - Posters (oversize), vol. 3, 1970 - 1981; F-115-2-0-0-20